hey guys so if we roll two dice one red
and one white what's the probability
that the red one is greater than the
white one if you want to try this on
your own pause it right now cuz I'm
going to solve it in 3 2 1 in order to
solve this let's make a table of all the
possible situations the red one can be
any number between one and six and the
white one can be any number between one
and six so we're interested in all the
places where the red one is greater than
the white one here's one example where
the red one's bigger than the white one
where the red is three and the white one
is two that's going to be this box right
here but we're interested in all the
situations where the red one is bigger
than the white one along this diagonal
the red one and the white one have the
exact same number so none of these are
going to work and then for all these
below the diagonal the white one is
going to be greater than the red one so
we can block all those out as well now
for all these remaining spots the red
one is going to be greater than the
white one so we can mark all of those so
the probability that red is greater than
white is these 15 successful outcomes
divided by the 36 total outcomes which
is approximately
41.67% how exciting